Inventory of the Preston Family Papers 1755-1826
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- John Preston Papers, 1785-1819., 8 items. (Folder 4)
  - Letter from Ja[me]s Blair, Abingdon, [Virginia], to John Preston, "Smithfield," Montgomery [County, Virginia], 29 July 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 4)
    Blair's wife, Betsy, a cousin of Preston, is unable to appear at court in Botetourt [County] in a case involving Mrs. [Elizabeth (Preston)] Madison, because her son is ill, but has sent a deposition. Hopes that Dr. Humphries has inoculated Preston's sisters for smallpox.
  - Letter from J[ohn] Preston, Fort Lee, Bluestone, [Virginia?], to the Governor, [Henry Lee], n.p., ante 8 May 1792., 3 pages. ADFS. (Folder 4)
    Explanation of his [Preston] actions taken in defending his posts by dispersing his men; also explanation of monies spent.
    Including ADF by John Preston, 13 June [17]92, Fort Lee, Bluestone, [Virginia], accounting for monies spent by him for his militia men. 2 pp. Also including typescript. 2 pp.
  - Letter from Edm[und] Randolph, Richmond, [Virginia ], to Gen[era]l John Preston, Horse Shoe Bottom, 7 May 1806., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 4)
    Concerning [legal] proceedings at Staunton; and proceedings of the Richmond chancery court concerning the McKin [?] case.
  - Letter from Ja[me]s Hoge, Buckingham County, [Virginia], to Gen[era]l John Preston, Richmond, Virginia, 2 Aug. 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 4)
    Requests to have orders countermanded and have his troops transferred somewhere where they can recover.
  - Letter from John Floyd, Washington City, [D.C ], to Gen[era]l John Preston, Richmond, Virginia, 4 Feb. 1819., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 4)
    The appropriations bill is before Congress and is expected to pass this week or early next week; the estimate for the ordinance department is $1,037,200.
  - Land grant certificate, 30 October 1819., 1 page. DS. (Folder 4)
    Land grant certificate of John Preston for 300 acres in Botetourt County, Virginia. Signed by Governor James P. Preston.
  Series 4: William C. Preston
- William C. Preston, 1827-1826., 3 items. (Folder 5)
  - Circular letter, August 1827., 4 pages. (Folder 5)
    Circular letter transmitting memorials of the citizens of Columbia and Richland, South Carolina, to the legislature of South Carolina, and to the Congress of the United States, protesting against the protective tariff.
    Also includes the text of the memorials. 2 pages. PDS. Including ALS from W[illia]m C. Preston, Chairman, n.p., to William B. Giles, Governor of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 2 Nov. 1827, explaining the attached circular. 1 page. Also including a NC1 of the proceedings of the committee. 1 page.
  - Letter from Thomas W. Gilmer, Capitol, Richmond, Virginia, to W[illia]m C. Preston, U.S. Senate, Washington, [D.C.], 18 March 1836., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 5)
    Asks name of a lawyer practicing in section in which Gen. Joseph S. Shelton of South Carolina lives. The estate of Gilmer's grandfather is being sued and Gen. Shelton is the principal debtor.
  - Letter from Epes Sargent, New York, [N.Y], to W[illia]m C. Preston, n.p., 31 Jan. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 5)
    Sargent is associated with Park Benjamin in publishing the New World, a New York newspaper, and discusses his efforts to bring about an international copyright agreement.